<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation | Joseph Luntadila</title>
    <link>/tags/innovation/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Innovation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Innovation</title>
      <link>/tags/innovation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best way to learn Entreprenuerial skills</title>
      <link>/project/sturent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/sturent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-entrepreneurship-by-building-a-startup-from-scratch-student-a-student-innovation-service&#34;&gt;Learning Entrepreneurship by building a Start-up from Scratch: Student, a student innovation service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project (in the top left) provides the link to the website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This project ran across two units Creating a New Venture Creation and TGP4: Building Something Completely New. The challenge was to create a start-up from scratch. That is, from idea, through customer-development to Business Plan. We had the opportunity to apply the tools and knowledge we have been learning from previous years from projects and workshops.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;task&#34;&gt;Task&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a Business Plan with evidence of product-market fit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;our-approach-and-my-role&#34;&gt;Our Approach and My Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jo316/Sturent/blob/master/DesignDocPoster.pdf&#34;&gt;Desing Process&lt;/a&gt;: explains the process team team underwent to produce the busniess idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had many activities that we divided into subactivities. As the head of the research, my role was to make sure that our research used appropriate tools for the task, and tracked the progress of the team. I also was responsable for quatitative, qualitative and visualisation in the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jo316/Sturent/blob/master/DSCN_Report1.pdf&#34;&gt;Prood of Problem and Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;
Produce a Proof of Problem: this shows that not only there is a problem that is painful enough to design a solution for, but also opportunities to bring about a solution. this included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 5-minutes video report of the problem we identified, impacts, scale and causes of the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 Page market research that supports the video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of methods and activities to produce the Proof of Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;compet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Competitor&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jo316/Sturent/blob/master/AwarenessCampaignReport.pdf&#34;&gt;Awerness Campaing&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://rb16730.wixsite.com/dscn&#34;&gt;MVP&lt;/a&gt; that we used to explain our solution to the target audience. It also was the tools that we used for testing and iterating.
This also was a accompanied by a report with the design choice and strategy for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jo316/Sturent/blob/master/AwarenessCampaignReport.pdf&#34;&gt; Campaign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;outcomes&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outcomes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We successfully designed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jo316/Sturent/blob/master/Business-Plan%20(1).pdf&#34;&gt;Business Plan&lt;/a&gt; that satisfied the acceptance criteria. That is, proving that a business is desirable, feasible and viable not in the paper, but through product-market fit and product-business-model fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;take-away&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take away&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not to take lean at its face value, rather take it as framework from which  a solution is built and tailor it to the learning from the data and insight from the market-research and customer development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One must believe in idea to work on it through, otherwise, obstacles will make giving up too easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
